alright thanks for meeting me for a
quick impromptu board meeting it's what
I called this so that discuss tomorrow's
board meeting that you aren't going to
be able to make so what I wanted to
discuss with you was changing the format
just like we changed the one with my
brother to be Fareed project raising
freaking people we can create this one
to be like our project crazy more we
have other people to come and help us
raise this project so even if they don't
want to take full ownership right if
they don't want to come and be on the
board they can come for that a week and
discuss like that week's issue and I
have no idea what that looks like and I
don't know even what like you know what
I mean what questions to tackle and so
that's what I wanted to discuss with you
is what do you think is like a question
I mean almost like an idea cafe of like
what's a question that we would want
other people to tackle like what's an or
what's our three aspirations like what
would this look like and then I get to
run it without you yeah oh good fine by
the way other people join just like yeah
that looks like it might be perfect
people might feel bad you're not gonna
be here and though that'd be four or
five people right like you never know
like sometimes these things happen for
the perfect time for the perfect reason
yeah although it's very short notice and
I apologize to that and it's like no I
think I think yeah I think that's a good
idea I like that I somewhere I think you
you told me that wouldn't or talked
about the different things to kind of
make that change so I think that's a
good idea yeah I haven't put much
thought into how we'd phrase that except
you know if if people you know it's the
project raising so it and it might also
just be for anyone that shows up I don't
leave in mind kind of leaving it open
like you and I when I'm around will have
things to discuss but if someone else
does show up then you're answering any
questions they have about it would be
good if if they're looking
for a topic then it could always be you
know still like we're still kind of
working on the pitch a bit so reviewing
the pitch with them seeing if it
resonates with them and then you know
what tech do they think would would be
the most useful for them what tech would
they think would be the most useful for
them to play now in game B or for them
yeah I mean if you're not gonna be here
we're not moving this for you know what
I mean like we're not making like actual
action items and moving forward why not
have the like big conversation of like
what is what does this look like which
is what I want to do anyways have more
people part of that conversation because
that's the inspirational part so they
want to do the break it down part by you
didn't like actually make things on but
that isn't as enticing to people I think
as like come one let's talk about game B
right like the bigger proto peon thing
that we're not in but we want to get in
and how does technology get us there and
only technology and what Tec can free us
from the game a tech that's limiting us
from going to game be like you know
we're using a Facebook group to discuss
game B and it's very it has some designs
in it that are very game a that that
push us down the game a path now I'm not
saying we need to replace Facebook right
now but but baby you know but the chance
of ever played see it right away is not
as like I need our own niche in creating
something we want and then yeah
eventually who wants Facebook doesn't
exist if there's an alternative that
people is actually an attractor mm-hmm
not like naughty love with Facebook
it is so interesting in game B that like
I just saw a post on someone talking
about kind of the recent friction that
the group has been happening in the
Facebook environment that some people
were kind of leaning back towards video
rather than written
so that would be once again a place
where we could use the idea cafe
scheduling software because it's still
it's so much work to get a group of
people together and really it's just
that part of finding some time and for
people scheduled and and in helping them
all agree to the time yeah
people question or whatever format it is
that you were having an actual
meaningful conversation around and then
the scheduling piece and that we've had
many discussion now I've got it figure
out like what what piece of that people
who haven't necessarily been part of the
board because people have imparted to
board meetings are being you and then
people who have been not on camera and
so I don't think those people are gonna
want to come on camera all of a sudden
maybe though it's more other people who
are like okay I can come and play at
this and they may have never heard about
it right and have anticipated so asking
what I mean it can be fairly open maybe
it is you know how we how tech that we
owned together it can help create game
be it be interesting also if someone
comes in to ask them what their thought
is about funding like what in for each
individual what would have to exist
before they would donate five or ten
dollars even if right now it's a token
if it's like you and me just doing that
a month and it's ten dollars you don't
have nothing but what what would they
have to I mean like is the idea enticing
enough that they would just chip in a
little bit to help build momentum or
would they need escape yeah is it
something I have to do every week my
question is like what would need to be
there before you would be willing to put
ten dollars a month in means like one
we're not asking you to put in ten
dollars a month but like what would
actually need to be in place what would
would value do you need to get out of it
for that to be worth it for you
which also has that conversation of
actual possible tech right like I don't
know I've no idea what it would be worth
but it's not Facebook right well what
about Facebook that you do own that you
see like is actually creating game B
right
actually you get a say in it you got to
participate in and you got to have video
conversations yeah I really like that
question and on that point just a
technical note we were talking about the
challenge of having one of us have like
or someone having to have a bank account
or something with this money stored and
they have to worry about all that it
turns out that they the open collective
which is a website for open source
software which we haven't discussed and
we kept that it's open that the software
could be closed source but I don't have
a compelling reason to do that if it is
open source they actually will manage
the bank account and everything and then
you just have a group of people that are
allowed to approve expenses so right now
you and I and then if a third person you
and I would have to give them permission
to be the third person yeah yeah for
them to do it we would need a hundred
likes on github which will be hard for
us because we're not writing the
software for developers which is what
normally github is we're writing this
for consumers and they don't normally go
into github and hit alike so that's one
challenge we'd have to get a hundred
likes likes or is that I feel like we
know we know enough people who know
github that like if they had five people
like like it would actually like listen
like it could be something I got
tomorrow right is like yeah github we
need to get a hundred likes people to
use their their software for finance so
yeah they would have to go in and create
an account and do that so yeah if we
could find a hundred people willing that
and that's really all it is is it's a
gate for them to not have to worry about
until they get a set number of interest
so I think it's fine since we'll be you
know since its kind of consumer driven
but it will be or user driven I don't
know the correct term that doesn't sound
like we're extracting people but I like
that remember so yeah member yeah I
think since we're kind of member focused
rather than developer focused you know a
little bit of we can play around the
edges I don't think anyone will scream
out
for begging for likes and if they do
then it's still for a good cause I don't
care all right what are they gonna do
take away our ever yeah and I have
several open source projects already so
you know at least arrow one person yeah
well yeah but but the main thing is you
know there is someone there is a
developer involved so it's not like
people subverting the process yeah so
that's that's that's an idea is so if
people come in and they're concerned
about the funding we could say well our
thought is maybe we'd use this open
collective as a as a way to manage the
funds which is always open and visible
and you know so if you don't like how
they're spending the funds you just
don't put any more in and usually it's
you know we're not people are putting
and hopefully something that is not you
know not big for their finances I mean
ten dollars a month isn't nothing to me
but at the same time I'm not you know
what I mean 30 years down the road I'm
gonna be like how could I have done that
I was so stupid
right like that's not my kids that's not
anything like one X less extra olate if
I treat myself during the month for
eight or ten extra like a job yeah and I
i don't--it donated to your brother's
patreon so that should be interesting it
is in the same position as we are where
it's hard to build the momentum but yeah
absolutely and there's so many people
like I think that once we have the
platforms to be able to kind of upvote
important projects what it gives the
person or confidences is something they
should be working on but like after
talking to the Spartan guy as well I was
like you need to be funded like this is
something we want you working on and I
feel that way about a lot of people in
this because other people aren't like I
don't think I would find you I don't
think there's enough like thing here
there's not enough meat on for me to
think this is a worthwhile project or I
don't know if you're the person not
slightly gave me space just in the world
in general and but there's people where
I'm like if I had a million if I had
millions of dollars I'm
like artist-in-residence like I'd be
Science and Technology residents like
this is where we want people focused and
it'd be great if the people with money
who might not hear about these things
could maybe funnel that money based on
interest right based on people like you
and I who maybe have two bucks a month
two bucks a week to spend on these
things to be like no this is like how
when Bernie Sanders gets money and it's
a bunch of money from different people
that means something very different than
a lot of money from a little right yeah
and so if there you can see that
somebody's making five thousand dollars
a month but it's art that's enough for
most people live off of you know making
five hundred dollars a month but it's
five hundred different people paying a
dollar you're gonna be more likely to
give them a few thousand if that's
within your budget
there those numbers make more sense we
don't need to fund you of your yeah and
also one concept of often thought about
is feature funding so when you want this
feature added to the main project or
this tool then you know you do a
crowdfunding for it
even as small as a little feature and
there are actually services that do that
but you know we could we could do it
throw up and collective or whatever but
yeah you would still need some sort of
funding for general management to keep
the machines on and there's security
breaks all the time that require
developer a couple hours to go in and
tweak things and keep things up to date
so we have to figure out like if you do
that a certain percentage of every
feature funding would have to have that
we'd have to have people that are that
are doing a regular monthly for them for
the maintenance budget but those are all
things we can discuss when we get down
to it if people if we have enough people
giving $10 a month and we know what that
budget is like you and I were even just
giving $10 a month that's $20 a month we
know our budget is right that we can yep
and that'll run the servers actually
that'll run like several servers these
days it's usually like five dollars a
month you can have something and there's
lots of free stuff most of my stuff is
actually hosted on free on github and
then although for the database you
usually need some money
it depends on how many people are using
under a certain thing you could get it
free from from Google fire store which I
use cuz it's easy but of course that's
you know kind of close technology and
it's Google and you know we don't want
to be funding a specific company so
we're gonna have to figure out what
technology we can use and how to how to
fund it but I have no problem if it's
cheap funding Google funding those
places well we're creating the things
that are like I'd rather put 50 bucks
towards something that Google owns that
gives us a thousand dollars worth of
value then finding the mom-and-pop
they'd already in place or recreating it
for ourselves when it's tens of
thousands like we need to figure out the
most bang for our buck and if there's
things available for free
we need to eventually get to the place
we're not relying on them but in the
beginning if it's free and it's Google
and Facebook
I'm good with using them because YouTube
to record our our information on like it
works and it's where the people are well
we're talking about what doesn't work
and how we can create something that's
even better for our individual selves
and collective alright the idea is I'm
gonna I'm not going to put this up on
the main part of game B but this what
we're talking about right now on this
video will be in the comment section and
I'll put up something for like come be
part of the live if you want you don't
want to be on video with me cuz that
lease has other you know other things to
do available something save the world
saving the world in his own way but so
now there's an opportunity to have to
have this right to like raise the tech
cooperative and come be part of a
conversation which is what would need to
be in place to entice you to pay $10 a
month for technology what is the debt
what is that technology at oh that
probably is look like yeah and I'll be
probably better than that but probably
right no I think that would be fine yeah
and you can order some it a little bit
if you want it'll work it'll work out
alright well I will not see you tomorrow
I'm turning 40 between now and the next
time I see you the night oh no no that's
not true we're gonna see
on Saturday right you're stuck up you're
coming to the project yeah awesome
all right so I'll be before you turn 40
well yeah it's a good age one of my
friends said his favorite age would be
50 and he's just about to turn 50 so
we'll see I'm not excited for like the
actual turning 240 but like the 40s and
like a whole new it was chaotic but
awesome I'm like 40s I don't know I'm
getting rid of chaos and just keeping
the awesome and like I'm sure yeah I'm
mid-40s it's it's been interesting so
I'm sure you'll enjoy it
so the passports all right sounds good
all right let's say enjoy your time
enjoy what you were doing when you're
not coming into the big what it seems
like it yeah anyway I will talk to you
on Saturday
you